jamesray.com 2007-03-04

# James Arthur Ray | Help zone | Create wealth in all areas of your life: Financial, Relational, Intellectual, Physical and Spiritual. Practical results through spiritual growth.

### Privacy statement

James Ray International values the relationship we have with our customers and are committed to responsible information handling practices.

James Ray International operates businesses, retail stores and Web sites under the name James Ray International ( _http://jamesray.com_ , _http://jamesrayinternational.com_ , _http://thepowertowin.com_ ). If you provide information to any of the above businesses, stores or Web sites, this information may be combined or shared between current or future James Ray International entities and subsidiaries.

Although our businesses, stores and Web sites have unique services and offerings, they share a similar privacy philosophy. James Ray International follows these privacy principles in our conduct in the collection, use, release and security of customer information both online and offline: 

  * Giving you CHOICES about how your data will be used. 
  * Providing you NOTICE of our information practices. 
  * Providing you the opportunity to UPDATE or CORRECT your personal information. 
  * Using information SECURITY safeguards. 
  * Limiting the SHARING of your information. 
  * Committing to COMPLYING with applicable privacy requirements. 
  * Providing you with means to CONTACT US about privacy-related issues. 

James Ray International may modify its privacy policy as needed consistent with these principles.

* * *

**PRIVACY POLICY**  
James Ray International

The following Privacy Policy describes the information and privacy practices for **James Ray International** retail sales and **_http://jamesray.com_**. You may read the privacy policies of each James Ray International subsidiary by visiting each entity's Web site or by emailing [webservices@jamesray.com](mailto:webservices@jamesray.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).

This Privacy Policy does not apply to other Web sites that may be accessible through the James Ray International sites. Our sites contain links to other sites operated by third parties, including but not limited to third party sites that display the James Ray International trademarks. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other sites to learn how they collect and use information about you.

To assist you with reading through our Privacy Policy, we have provided answers to questions that you may find most important: 

  * What information does James Ray International **COLLECT** and how is the information **USED**?
  * Do James Ray International Web sites use **COOKIES** or **OTHER TECHNOLOGIES** to collect information?
  * Does James Ray International **SHARE** the information I've provided?
  * Do I have **CHOICES** regarding how my information is used?
  * How can I **UPDATE** or **CHANGE** my information?
  * How does James Ray International **SECURE** my personal information?
  * Does James Ray International collect information from **CHILDREN**?
  * Whom can I **CONTACT** if I have questions or concerns?
  * Will this Privacy Policy **CHANGE**?

* * *

**What information does James Ray International COLLECT and how is the information USED?**

**What information we collect.** We collect personal information such as your contact information (name, e-mail address), billing/shipping information (credit card number, shipping address), or your personal preferences (product wish-lists, hobbies, likes and dislikes relating to the products we may sell). When submitting personal information on an online form, we will identify which fields are required in order to fulfill your request. Additionally, our Web server automatically collects click-stream information such as the address (or "URL") of the Web site that you came from before visiting our site, which pages you visit on our site, which browser you used to view our site and any search terms you have entered on our site.

**When we collect information.** While shopping or taking advantage of services available at James Ray International, businesses or visiting our Web sites, we may ask that you provide certain information about yourself. For example, we request personal information when you set up an account online, purchase products or services, join a frequent buyer program, participate in a sweepstakes, promotion or survey, contact James Ray International with a question or concern, access a free resource, or participate in other activities. In addition, when using our Web sites, our servers may collect click-stream information as described above. James Ray International may also obtain information or lists from other companies.

**How the information is used.** We use the information you provide in order to 1) fulfill requests for products, services or information, 2) administer shopping or reward club accounts, 3) provide customer services, 4) administer contests or promotions, 5) offer new products and services, 6) measure and improve the effectiveness of our Web sites or our marketing endeavors, 7) tailor our online offerings to your preferences, and 8) other business purposes. James Ray International will provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of having your information used for marketing communications.

* * *

**Do James Ray International Web sites use COOKIES or OTHER TECHNOLOGIES to collect information?**

**Cookies --** A "cookie" is a small data file that a Web site may send to your browser and which may then be stored on your system. Our Web sites use cookies to simulate a continuous connection -- cookies let us "remember" information about your preferences and passwords and allow you to move within our Web sites without reintroducing yourself. We use cookie and web beacon technology to track which pages on our sites our visitors view and which Web browsers our visitors use. We also use "action tags" to assist in delivering the cookie. These action tags allow us to compile statistics and other data about our customers on an aggregate basis, by embedding a random identifying number on each user's browser. Then we track where that number shows up on our site. We share aggregated data (information that does not identify you) with third parties.

**Third Party Service Providers --** Our Web sites may use third party service providers to serve ads and e-mails on our behalf. These companies may use technologies similar to those outlined above to measure the effectiveness of ads and e-mails and use information about your visits to this and other Web sites so that we can provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. For this purpose, we may also provide these third party service providers anonymous information about your site navigation and purchases. 

* * *

**Does James Ray International SHARE the information I've provided?**

James Ray International may need to share personal information with third parties in limited circumstances. For example, we may release personal information to third parties to: perform services on our behalf, fulfill our customer's orders, send marketing communications, deliver packages, send postal mail and email, or process credit card payments.

_http://jamesray.com_ is an affiliated entity and a wholly owned subsidiary of James Ray International. As such, any information you may provide to us either online or offline may be combined or shared between current or future James Ray International entities and subsidiaries.

From time to time, we may be required to provide personal information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain personal information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and ourselves. We may also release personal information in the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event.

* * *

**Do I have CHOICES regarding how my information is used?**

If your information is currently being used to send you marketing communications, you can opt-out at any time. All marketing e-mail and direct mail communications from James Ray International, such as hot deals or special offers, tell you how to stop receiving them.

To opt-out of receiving marketing material from James Ray International: 

  1. Follow directions on a marketing e-mail or direct mail communication from us. 
  2. Call 760-476-9077 
  3. Send an email with your current contact information to [webservices@jamesray.com](mailto:webservices@jamesray.com?subject=Opt%20Out)
  4. Send a request with your current contact information to:  
James Ray International  
Attn: Privacy Manager  
2386 Faraday Avenue Suite 110  
Carlsbad, CA 92008 

James Ray International will take reasonable steps to implement your request to opt out. However, please note that due to production and mailing timelines, it may take around six weeks to make the requested change and, until that change takes effect, you may still receive promotional information from us. 

* * *

**How can I UPDATE or CHANGE my information?**

James Ray International wants your information and preferences to be accurate and complete. We provide several different methods for you to update or change the information you give us.

To **update** or **change** your information: 

  1. If you've created an account on _http://jamesray.com_ , you can update your information after logging into your account. 
  2. You can send e-mail using our General Questions contact form: [Click here](http://jamesray.com/help.php?section=contactus&mode=update). 
  3. Send a request to:  
James Ray International  
Attn: Customer Care  
2386 Faraday Avenue Suite 110  
Carlsbad, CA 92008 
  4. Call 760-476-9077 

* * *

**How does James Ray International SECURE my personal information?**

Whether you are shopping online or on the phone with an James Ray International representative, we have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, unauthorized access and alteration of the information under our control.

**Safe Shopping Policy**  
Because your credit card security is a high priority, we have taken numerous steps to ensure that your payment information is processed confidentially, accurately and securely. The _http://jamesray.com_ Web site uses encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), to protect your credit card information during data transport. SSL encrypts ordering information such as your name, address, and credit card number.

Some older browser versions and some firewalls don't permit communication through secure servers. In that case, you'll be unable to securely sign in to your account or purchase products. You may choose to sign in to your account or purchase products through our non-SSL enabled server, but your password will not be encrypted. This can be done by visiting the Logon page at [_http://jamesray.com/checkout.php_](http://jamesray.com/checkout.php). If you have already securely saved billing information to your account, you can still order securely using your saved information. However, if you submit new billing information through the non-SSL enabled server, it will not be encrypted.

**Choosing a Personal Password**  
When you create an online account at _http://jamesray.com_ , you need to select a personal password that you will remember. It must be at least 6 characters. To maximize your level of protection, you should choose a combination of both letters and numbers. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords or any account information.

Although we cannot guarantee against any loss, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, alteration or destruction of data, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. James Ray International cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us by email and you do so at your own risk.

* * *

**Does James Ray International collect information from CHILDREN?**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. We will not knowingly or intentionally collect personal information online from children under the age of 14.

* * *

**Whom can I CONTACT if I have questions or concerns?**

Please contact our Privacy Manager to report any known or suspected privacy or security breaches or to submit privacy-related questions or complaints. After receiving your inquiry, we will respond within five business days. You may contact us in the following ways: 

  1. Postal Mail:  
James Ray International  
Attn: Privacy Manager  
2386 Faraday Avenue Suite 110  
Carlsbad, CA 92008 
  2. Email: [webservices@jamesray.com](mailto:webservices@jamesray.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy)
  3. Phone: 760-476-9077 

* * *

**Will this Privacy Policy CHANGE?**

Because our Web sites will continue to implement new technologies and improve the services and features we provide, this policy is subject to change. If there are changes or additions to this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here or in other formats we deem acceptable, so that you will always know what information we collect online or offline, how we use it and what choices you have. If we change our information practices or this Privacy Policy in such a way that your personal information may be used or shared in a different manner, we will give you the choice to opt-out of having your past information used or shared in that new manner.

**Last revision date:** October 21, 2004  
James Ray International has reviewed and rewritten its Privacy Policy to (1) make it easier to read and understand, (2) describe its practices in better detail, (3) make it clear that we may combine or share the information we hold across all current or future James Ray International entities, and (4) combine privacy policies and practices for James Ray International retail stores, _http://jamesray.com_ and its affiliates. Instead of having multiple and potentially conflicting privacy policies for James Ray International and our Web sites, we have decided to ensure all James Ray International operations follow the same privacy standards. By combining our privacy policies and practices, we give our customers the same privacy standards whether providing James Ray International personal information on or offline. If you have questions about our Privacy Policy, email our Privacy Manager at [webservices@jamesray.com](mailto:webservices@jamesray.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy).
